<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grants | Formal Verification Group</title>
    <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/tag/grants/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://fiction-zju.github.io/tag/grants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Grants</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://fiction-zju.github.io/media/sharing.jpeg</url>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/tag/grants/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSFC General Program Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-08-27-grant-nsfc-general-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-08-27-grant-nsfc-general-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal has been granted for funding by the NSFC General Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Fixed-Point Theories for Quantitative Verification and Symbolic Inference of Probabilistic Programs&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (NSFC) as a General Program. The project aims to establish a universal fixed-point semantic model for loopy probabilistic programs possibly exhibiting divergent behaviors and conditioning. It seeks for a comprehensive system of theories, methods, and techniques for automated quantitative verification and highly accurate symbolic inference of probabilistic programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerospace Open Fund Project Proposal Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-07-18-grant-aerospace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-07-18-grant-aerospace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal has been granted for funding by the China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Requirement-Driven Test Generation and Prioritization for Aerospace Embedded Software&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the High-Reliability Embedded Software Engineering Technology Lab. of China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC). This project aims to develop a fine-grained framework for the automatic generation and prioritization of validation-testing scripts and oracles for aerospace embedded software by leveraging the integrated power of large language models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCF-Huawei Project Proposal Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-06-06-grant-huyanglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/25-06-06-grant-huyanglin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal has been granted for funding by the CCF-Huawei Populus Grove Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Modular Verification by Integrating Large Language Models with Symbolic Reasoning&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the joint Populus Grove Fund of the China Computer Federation (CCF) and Huawei. This project aims to develop a lightweight verification (and testing) framework for operating system kernels by leveraging the integrated power of large language models (mainly for specification synthesis) and symbolic reasoning techniques (e.g., static analysis, symbolic execution, and automated theorem proving). The key to this framework is a fine-grained, compositional procedure of refining verification specifications and obligations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZJNSF Project Proposal Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-12-08-grant-zjnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-12-08-grant-zjnsf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal has been granted for funding by the ZJNSF Major Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Hybrid Computational Models and Theories for Heterogeneous Quantum-Super-Intelligent Computing&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the Zhejiang Provincial Natural Science Foundation (ZJNSF) as a Major Program. This project aims to develop hybrid computational models and theories for emerging computing paradigms consisting of distributed, heterogeneous quantum-, super-, and intelligent-computing infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSFC Excellent Young Scientists Fund (Overseas) Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-10-13-grant-nsfc-excellent-young-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-10-13-grant-nsfc-excellent-young-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prof. Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://fiction-zju.github.io/author/mingshuai-chen/&#34;&gt;Mingshuai Chen&lt;/a&gt; is awarded the NSFC Excellent Young Scientists Fund Program (Overseas).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Formal Design of Safety-Critical Cyber-Physical Systems&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (NSFC) as an Excellent Young Scientists Fund Program (Overseas). This program is known as one of the most prestigious grants for young researchers across China. The project aims to carry out research under the umbrella of automated synthesis of cyber-physical systems by exploring mechanized principles for designing complex safety-critical systems while aiming to establish cutting-edge synthesis techniques powered by verification methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCF-Huawei Project Proposal Granted</title>
      <link>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-07-26-grant-huyanglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiction-zju.github.io/news/23-07-26-grant-huyanglin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal has been granted for funding by the CCF-Huawei Populus Grove Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project proposal titled &amp;ldquo;Self-Adaptive Abstract Interpretation for C Programs&amp;rdquo; has been granted for funding by the joint Populus Grove Fund of the China Computer Federation (CCF) and Huawei. This project aims to develop formal techniques for automating the procedure of abstract interpretation for analyzing C/C++ programs where, in particular, we explore a mechanism for (semi-)automatically adapting the abstract domains and refinement strategies during static analysis of real-world, industry-scale programs, in the hope of improving efficiency and reducing the rate of false alarms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
